totango.com 2015-03-29

# Privacy Policy | Totango

Like any cloud based offering, Totango understands that by using our services you are entrusting us with business critical and sensitive information. As such, we take serious measures, technical and procedural, to ensure data is kept secure and private and within your control. Totango, LLC has been awarded TRUSTe’s Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe’s program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/) and the [TRUSTed Cloud Program Requirements](http://trusted%20cloud%20program%20requirementstrusted%20cloud%20program%20requirements/) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site, [http://totango.com](http://totango.com/) and Through the Totango Services.

TRUSTe’s mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy Trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at privacy@totango.com. If you are not satisfied with our response you can [contact TRUSTe here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request).

Totango, LLC complies with the U.S. – E.U. Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal data from the from European Union member countries. Totango, LLC has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Totango, LLC’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

You can read our complete privacy policy further down this page. The highlights for those of us that are not interested in legal wording:

## The Highlights

  *  It’s your data. At your request, we will provide you a full digital copy of your data and/or permanently remove all copies of it from our databases. You can request this at any time, from the first moment you signup for free trial, throughout your subscription and after. You decide what information to store in your Totango data-store, what parameters and for which accounts.

  * We will never use your data without your permission. We will not sell, resell or otherwise share your data with 3rd parties, either before, during or after your subscription with us. From time to time, Totango compiles industry wide benchmarks for the benefit of the online software community. These are always aggregated benchmarks, conducted from anonymized versions of customer data and cannot be linked back to individual accounts. You can decide to opt-out from these benchmarks at any time.

  * Your data is secure with Totango. Totango follows generally accepted industry standards to keep your data safe & secure. Communications to and from Totango are encrypted using state of the art SSL technology. Additionally we provide application-layer security features to further anonymize your sensitive data.

## Full Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy covers the privacy practices that Totango LLC. (“Totango”, “we”, “us”, or “our”) employs in providing the Totango Service (the “Service”) to our customers, including their personnel (collectively, “Customer(s)”). It explains what data we collect, including Personally our Identifiable Information (defined below), about (i) Customers; and (ii) the customers and clients of our Customers (“End Users”), and how we collect, use and retain such data. The use of information collected through our service shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which our clients have engaged Totango.

1\. Introduction. We are committed to respecting privacy and recognize the need for appropriate protection and management of any Personally Identifiable Information that is shared with us as part of the Service. As used in this Privacy Policy, “Personally Identifiable Information” means any information that may be used, either alone or in combination with other information, to personally identify an individual, including, but not limited to, a first and last name, personal profile, a home or other physical address, an email address or other contact information.

2\. Totango Service Description. We provide the Service in order to enable our Customers to collect information about their End Users’ activities on their web service and/or other software services offering (“Customer Service”) and to provide our Customers with a global view of those activities.

3\. What Information We Collect and How We Collect It. As the provider of the Service, we receive and/or collect data, which may contain Personally Identifiable Information, in the following ways:

3.1. Customer Account Information. As part of the Service, we may collect or obtain information (including Personally Identifiable Information) that a Customer provides about itself, such as the Customer’s account name, and email address, company information and related information about its personnel (“Customer Data”).

3.2. End User Data. As part of the Service, a Customer may provide us with data, including Personally Identifiable Information, such as a user’s email address to store on the Customer’s behalf about an End User in connection with the End User’s use of the Customer Service (“End User Data”). Totango has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. We work with our Customers to help them provide notice to their End Users concerning the purpose for which personal information is collected. We may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the service agreements with our Clients.

3.3. Transactions. We may collect or obtain information, including Personally Identifiable Information, from each Customer in order to complete the Customer’s subscription to the Service. Such information could include a credit card number, related account and billing information, and other data required to process the order. We may update such data should a Customer grant us permission to bill a credit card for recurring charges, such as monthly or other types of periodic payments. We may use the tools, software or services of third party service providers to process transactions on our behalf, in which case the terms of use and/or privacy policy of said third party service provider shall also apply to the transaction. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

3.4 We may collect 3rd party data, such as email, if you use our “Ask an Engineer” feature. Totango stores this information for the sole purpose of sending them an invitation to the Totango account. If you are a 3rd party and wish us to remove this information, please contact us at Privacy@totango.com

3.5. Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies. Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Totango and our partners  e.g. marketing partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers e.g. online customer support provider, etc. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

3.6. Analytics / Log Files. As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically using Analytics technology and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We do not link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information.

3.7. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as HTML 5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. To manage LSOs please click here: http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html

We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking [Here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union click [Here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)) . Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

4\. The Way We Use Information.

4.1. We will use the Customer Data of a Customer to provide and improve our Service to the Customer, to contact the Customer, and to identify and authenticate the Customer’s access to our services that the Customer is authorized to access.

4.2. We will store End User Data on behalf of the related Customer in order to provide the Service to that Customer.

4.3. We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell your personal information to third parties.

4.4. We may engage third party hosting providers to store information, including Personally Identifiable Information, on our behalf. Such information may be stored on servers located in different countries around the world. We only engage third party hosting providers that post a privacy policy governing their processing of Personally Identifiable Information.

4.5. We may transfer Personally Identifiable Information to our affiliated companies located in other countries around the world in order for them to perform business functions or services for us or on our behalf, such as customer service. We require that these affiliated companies agree to process such information in compliance with our Privacy Policy. Any information provided to these companies is used only as necessary to provide these services to us.

4.6. We will retain your information for as long as your account is active. We reserve the right to retain any Personally Identifiable Information, End User data we process on behalf of our Customers and other Service-related data for such time as we are providing the Service to the Customer to which the information relates and for a reasonable time thereafter.We will retain and use information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements

4.7 If your Personally Identifiable Information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update or amend by making the change in your account/profile settings page orby emailing our Customer Support. We will respond to your request to access within 30 days. Totango has no direct relationship with the individual End Users’s personal data it may processes. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, delete inaccurate data or withdraw consent for further contact should direct his query to the Totango customer they deal with directly. If the Client requests Totango to remove the data, we will respond to their request within 30 days In any event, we will delete or amend any Customer’s or End User’s Personally Identifiable Information that we are storing if we receive a written request to do so. Any such request should be addressed to [privacy@totango.com](mailto:privacy@totango.com?subject=Privacy%20Request) and include sufficient information for Totango to identify the Customer or End User and the information to delete or amend.

4.8. Email Opt-Out. If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), (accessable from our blog page) we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your account settings page or you can contact us at privacy@totango.com

4..9. Notwithstanding the foregoing, we may disclose Personally Identifiable Information or any information that we receive in connection with the Service if we have a good faith belief that disclosure of such information is helpful or reasonably necessary to (i) comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request; or (ii) protect against harm to the rights, property or safety of Totango, our Customers, End Users, or the public.

5\. Anonymous Information. We may use Anonymous Information (defined below), or disclose it to third party service providers, to provide, improve and/or develop the Service. From time to time, we may disclose Anonymous Information as part of our participation in an industry wide benchmark for the benefit of the online software community. Each Customer may opt-out from such benchmarks at any time by emailing us at privacy@totango.com. “Anonymous Information” means information which does not enable identification of an individual user, such as aggregated information, about the use of the Service.

6\. Children’s Privacy. The Service is not structured to attract children under the age of 18. Accordingly, we do not intend to collect Personally Identifiable Information from anyone we know to be under 18 years.

7\. In the Event of Merger, Sale, or Change of Control. We may transfer or assign this Privacy Policy and any Personally Identifiable Information to a third party entity that acquires or is merged with Totango as part of a merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control (“Change of Control”). Should such a Change of Control occur, Totango will use reasonable efforts to direct the transferee to use the Personally Identifiable Information in a manner that is consistent with Totango’s privacy policies. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your Personally Identifiable Information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your Personally Identifiable Information.

8\. Security. The security of Personally Identifiable Information is important to us. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the Personally Identifiable Information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. We use SSL technology to encrypt data during transmission, and we also employ application-layer security features to further anonymize sensitive data (such as your credit card information) . However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect Personally Identifiable Information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

9\. Blog/Forum. Our Web site offers a publicly accessible blog and a community support forum which allow user generated comments. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your Personally Identifiable Information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [privacy@totango.com](mailto:privacy@totango.com?subject=Privacy%20Request). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your Personally Identifiable Information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. Our blog is also managed by a third party application that may require you to register to post a comment. We do not have access or control of the information posted to the blog that is managed by a third party application. You will need to contact or login into the third party application if you want the personal information that was posted to the comments section removed. To learn how the third party application uses your information, please review their privacy policy.

10\. Single Sign on. On certain pages of our site, such as the support forum or the careers page, you can access their functionality by using an an authentication service such as Twitter, Google or “Apply with Linkedin”. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address. Services like these may give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network.

11\. Social Media Widgets. Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button, the Share this button and other interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

12\. Testimonials. We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [privacy@totango.com](mailto:privacy@totango.com?subject=Privacy%20Request).

13\. Links to 3rd Party Sites. Our Site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Totango, LLC. If you submit Personally Identifiable Information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Web site you visit.

14\. Modification. We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change the terms of this Privacy Policy at any time. Such change will become effective thirty (30) days following notification to our Customers by email or by posting an updated version on our website [www.totango.com](https://www.totango.com/) and shall not affect Personally Identifiable Information collected prior to the date when the change becomes effective.

15\. Contacting Us. Any comments, concerns, complaints, or questions regarding our Privacy Policy may be addressed to: [privacy@totango.com](mailto:privacy@totango.com?subject=Privacy%20Request) or

Totango LLC   
1200 Park Pl #200   
San Mateo, CA 94403   
United States   
(800) 634-1990 

Effective Date: 08/16/2014
